Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Company Histories, Memoirs and Reminiscences, 1890s-2010 and undated
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
J. Walter Thompson Company. Company Histories, Memoirs and Reminiscences 1890s-2010 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
J. Walter Thompson Company.
3.5 Linear Feet 1500 Items
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States.
The JWT Company Histories, Memoirs and Reminiscences collection spans the years 1890-2010 and includes correspondence, company histories, employee memoirs, biographies and reminiscences collected by the JWT New York Office's Information Center. Some histories include client lists and individual campaign case histories. Histories of individual JWT offices include Rome, Chicago, and London. Includes narratives written by James Webb Young, James Kennedy, Charles Raymond, Colin Dawkins and George Richardson Jr. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Company Histories, Memoirs and Reminiscences were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1987-2010.
Collection Overview
The JWT Company Histories, Memoirs and Reminiscences collection spans the years 1890-2009 and includes correspondence, company histories, employee memoirs, biographies and reminiscences collected by the JWT New York Office's Information Center. Some histories include client lists and individual campaign case histories. Histories of individual JWT offices include Rome, Chicago, and London. Includes narratives written by James Webb Young, Howard Henderson, James Kennedy, Charles Raymond, Colin Dawkins and George Richardson Jr.
Collection Arrangement
Organized into two series: General Company Histories Files and Memoirs and Reminiscences. General Company Histories Files include correspondence, historical letterheads and historical narratives written by various JWT employees. Memoirs and Reminiscences include personal narratives of the authors' career at JWT. Large-format items have been relocated to Oversize Materials. Original folder titles were maintained where possible. Arranged alphabetically.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
J. Walter Thompson Company
J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office
J. Walter Thompson Company. Rome Office
J. Walter Thompson Company -- History
Young, James Webb, 1886-
Advertising agencies -- United States
Advertising agencies -- United States -- History
Advertising executives
Autobiography
Memoirs and biographies
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections within the J. Walter Thompson Company Archives.
Artifacts and Memorabilia
Biographical Information
Corporate Documentation
Iconographic Collection
Arnold Grisman Papers
Colin Dawkins Papers
Howard Henderson Papers
James Webb Young Papers
Samuel W. (Samuel William) Meek Papers
Sam Soper Papers
Sidney Ralph Bernstein Company Histories Files
William James Carlton Diaries and Biography
Contents of Collection
- General Company Histories Files, 1890s-1991 and undated
  - Advertising awards, 1924-1974, (3 folders) (Box 1)
    [Some items removed to Oversize Materials]
  - Autographs and letterhead, 1890s-1982
  - Biography of Ronald T. Wentzel (JWT South Africa), 1993
  - Centennial, 1963-1965, (2 folders)
  - Company Histories project, 1978
  - Correspondence and memoranda, 1914-1943
  - Employee-written histories
    - General, 1928-1983, (1-3 of 9 folders)
    - General, 1928-1983 (continued), (4-9 of 9 folders) (Box 2)
    - David Campbell-Harris, history of JWT in Italy, 1976
    - Frankie McKee Robins (JWT Information Center), notes on Wm. James Carlton, 1961-1965, (2 folders)
    - Gerry Broderick, JWT--Who Is It?, 1983
    - Howard Henderson, A Short History of the J. Walter Thompson Co., 1960
    - Howard Henderson, Some Basic Roots of the J. Walter Thompson Co., 1958
    - Jane Ellen Murray, history of JWT Chicago, 1979
    - Julián Bravo, J. Walter Thompson España from 1927 to 1936, undated (translated by Sharon Gordon, JWT New York)
    - Tom Rayfield, Fifty in 40 (JWT London), 1996 (Box 3)
  - J. Walter Takeover: From Divine Right to Common Stock, Richard Morgan, 1991
  - JWT History: Departments, Clients, Case Histories, circa 1961
  - New Techniques Group, 1937-1938
  - Office histories
    - J. Walter Thompson Company Chronology, 1987
    - JWT 130th anniversary proclamation and presentations, 1994
    - London Office, 1970
    - Los Angeles/Hollywood Office, 1959-1976 and undated
    - San Francisco Office, 1946-1978 and undated
  - Owl as trademark, 1947-1963
  - Stockholder affidavits, 1923
- Memoirs and Reminiscences, 1928-2009 and undated
  - Carroll Carroll, Remembrances of Radio Things Past, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Charles Raymond, 1928-1956, (1-2 of 11 folders)
  - Charles Raymond, 1928-1956 (continued), (3-11 of 11 folders)
  - Colin Campbell Dawkins, Adventures in the Ad Game, circa 1985 (Box 5)
  - Ellsworth Frankson, From Trainee to Thompson Man in a Decade 1960-1970, 2009
  - George Butler (JWT London), Bush House, Berlin and Berkeley Square, 1985
  - George Partridge Richardson Jr., JWT and Me!, circa 1986, (2 folders)
  - James Kennedy, Facts and Fables of an Advertising Man and other writings, 1981 and undated
  - Noel Delbridge, Gladman, 2010
  - Russell Pierce (JWT Buenos Aires), Gringo-Gaucho: An Advertising Odyssey, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Sam Soper (JWT London), My JWT Life 1932-1971, 1996
  - Taylor Adams, 1974
  - Tom Rayfield (JWT London), Dear Personalised, 1992
  - Tom Rayfield (JWT London), Dear Sir or Madam, 1994
- Oversize Materials
  - Advertising awards, 1927-1974 (Box OV1)
  - Centennial, 1964, (2 folders)
  - Letterhead, 1896
  - London Office, history and clippings, 1962-1990, (2 folders)
  - Organizational charts, undated